

KAUMUDI SAWANT

CONTACT

Thane, India 400608

9869806422

kaumudik3@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Recruitment
- · Benefits administration
- · Data-Driven decision-making
- · Diversity and inclusion
- Ethical leadership
- Talent management systems
- Project management tools
- Succession planning
- · Strategic resource allocation
- Dispute Resolution

SUMMARY

Dependable HR professional with extensive experience in planning, directing and coordinating HR policies. Skilled in various staff affairs such as hiring, appraisals and firing. Excellent problem-solver, talented at troubleshooting and remedying staff issues and complaints.

EXPERIENCE

Manager- HR, 08/2022 - Current Prasham Constructions & Engineering Pvt. Ltd

- · Lead HR projects like compensation plans revisions
- Implement functional HRMS and internal databases across all departments and locations
- Oversee our payroll and performance evaluation systems
- · Design company policies and procedures
- Review and update our employment contracts and agreements
- Prepare budgets by department
- Track key HR metrics like cost per hire and retention rates
- Manage internal communication projects (like job satisfaction surveys)
- Measure the effectiveness of our benefits programs and recommend improvements
- Coordinate employee training and development initiatives.

HR Manager, 03/2016 - 08/2022 Jupiter Hospital

- Recommended, initiated and finalized HR actions regarding faculty and staff position management, compensation and employment postings, hiring proposals and new hire onboarding
- Facilitated onboarding sessions and on-the-job training for new hires bolstering position knowledge and skillset
- Implemented performance reviews and motivational strategies to elevate HR team results
- Proficiency in manpower management & recruitment process entailing resume generation, screening and short-listing with appropriate compensation
- Motivated employees through special events and incentive programs
- Guided leaders and employees on company policies, programs, benefits and salary administration
- Managed employee disputes by employing conflict resolution techniques
- Supervised and mentored direct reports and developed talented HR teams.

Sr. HR Executive, 03/2015 - 12/2015 Sancheti Hospital

- Directed hiring and onboarding programs for new employees
- Met with employees annually for progress reviews and performance assessments

- Educated employees on company policy and kept employee handbook current
- Facilitated new-hire onboarding processes, generating offer letters and processing background checks
- Supervised details of personnel transfers and promotions
- Maintained open-door policy to encourage employee communication and conflict resolution
- Reviewed and responded to urgent HR-related escalations
- Maintained and developed job descriptions, onboarding handbooks and training programs
- Managed integration, configuration and administration of HR systems.

HR Executive, 09/2012 - 12/2014 Dr. Batra's Positive Health Clinic

- Maintained and developed job descriptions, onboarding handbooks and training programs
- Made recommendations for corrective action in employees with performance issues
- Managed integration, configuration and administration of HR systems
- Facilitated new-hire onboarding processes, generating offer letters and processing background checks
- Reviewed and responded to urgent HR-related escalations.

EDUCATION

Masters in Personnel Management & Industrial Relations, 06/2012 Jankidevi Bajaj Institute of Management Studies

BA in Philosophy, 06/2010 D G Ruparel College